[music]
Um let's get started. So today I wanted
to talk about um testing and securing AI
generated code with cursor. Um the main
theme of the event is that um um we
generate a lot of code using cursor but
a lot of times you know um the models
are hallucinating or they're not doing
exactly what you intend to do and
sometimes there's a security issues and
um a lot of bugs inside of it. So it's
not really you know u useful in terms of
deploying apps in production using
cursor [snorts] or when you're working
on a real app. uh you don't want uh you
know any issues or bugs uh going with
your code. Um um so that's what I'm
going to talk about today. Um so who am
I? Uh my name is Trey. I'm a cursor
ambassador for Canada and a senior AI
engineer. I'm working at a startup uh
called Vivven in San Francisco. Um um I
also run a assisted assisted coding
workshops on different platforms and
I've been speaking at various
conferences about AI coding as well. Um,
I started using AI to code back in 2020
uh with GitHub copilot. So, it's been
about 5 years since I've been coding
using AI and I've uh try to figure out
different workflows that allow me to
move really really fast with AI while
maintaining the quality and u speed. Um,
so uh for those of you uh who are not
aware of cursor uh cursor is uh your AI
sidekick in your development workflow.
It acts as your parcoder. It's just a
fork of VS code. So if you're already
familiar with VS Code, it's a really
easy migration to um just work with
cursor. Um
now uh what makes cursor different than
other uh tools that are out there,
right? Uh so there's like cloud code,
there's amp code, there's ko, um there's
all all sort of the different tools that
uh make uh coding using AI really really
easy. But what I particularly love about
cursor is that it it's it makes context
engineering really really easy. And
we're going to see how it makes it
really really easy. And I've never seen
any other tool um do this more
efficiently. Um um so I I so I think
that's the secret sauce behind cursor
like they just make context engineing
really really easy. As we know that
these agents um you know love um um
love to guess things but if you uh you
know give it proper context it's not
going to hallucinate and as a result of
that you're going to get much better
output. Um so cursor kind of does a lot
of context engineering behind the scenes
for you. Um that's what makes it
different. It's it's it's not about you
know um proing different models and the
UI. Um
so um how many of you guys um use cursor
rules uh user rules and project rules
like I I I wanted to get a sense of like
how people use cursor in this room so
that I can tailor the session
accordingly. Um can you guys raise your
hands if you are uh using cursor rules?
All right. And how many of you guys are
aware of uh project rules and user rules
and then also bugbot rules and stuff
like that. Have you guys used those
extensively or not?
Okay. So I see very few handresses
meaning that I think I might need to
cover the basics of user rules and
project rules. So I'll probably start
with that. So user rules is basically
global to your cursor environment.
Meaning that it applies to all of your
project um and it's going to be used by
all of your agent chats and applies to
all of the chat threads that you uh
start with cursor. Meaning that every
single time you send a message to cursor
your user rule or your global rule is
going to apply to that. Um second type
of rule is project rules. So these are
scoped for the specific project. Um so
they can be invoked or used path
patterns. They can be in invoked
manually meaning that you have to like
manually attach the specific rule to the
context or it could be also based on the
relevance. Um so this apply
intelligently part that is right here.
Um it's kind of like cloud skills. Um
cursor had it like for over a year at
this point. So the agent can decide when
to pull in that context depending on
what you're doing, right? Um and then it
can be applied to specific files or it
can be applied manually and can be
always applied um as well for the
specific project. And what most people
don't know is that um you can actually
create cursor rules in each module of
your project. So if you're working in a
monor repo, if you have like front end
and back end in the same repository, you
can actually have uh cursor rules in
each of the front end and back end and
then those rules will be applied for
front end and back end accordingly. So
that way like you are doing proper
context engineering. One way I use it is
actually by giving the agents memory of
what's inside of that module. every
single time the agent is going to read
that read a file or work on that
specific module it's actually going to
take a look at the memory for that
module and then work on that and once
it's done working it's also going to
update that memory autonomously to keep
that up to date as well so that's like
one of the most powerful uses of using
cursor rules and uh subdirectories uh in
cursor um let's actually uh try this out
um in action so feel free to open any
project that you have um or you and just
open cursor um just a regular you know
empty cursor as well. So I'm probably
going to do that just for the sake of
this uh demo. So I'm going to create a
sample test folder here.
>> Could you zoom in?
>> Yeah, I'll actually do a couple of
things. Uh cursor settings. Let me make
the theme white.
Uh
oh, sorry. It's a
cursor light.
So, that should help. And then
going to zoom in a little bit.
>> All right. [sighs] Are you guys able to
see the screen now?
>> Perfect. All right. So, I'm going to get
rid of this for now. Um, [clears throat]
I don't have anything right now.
If I go and take a look at my user
rules,
I'll have something. Um, let me
So, these are the rules that come with
all the projects, right? So, for
example, I work a lot with cloud 4.5
sonnet and it just likes to create a lot
of markdown files. Um, I hate it. uh it
keeps telling me I'm absolutely right
all the time. I hate it. So that's all
is going to going into my user rule. So
it doesn't do that. Um it actually now
just creates uh text files and not
markdown files but it still creates
summary in the files. Uh point is you
can u be open-ended about what you want
to um have in
your cursor your rules. Basically, if
you have a coding style and you want
your agent to represent your own coding
style, those kind of things uh go into
your user rules, global rules, which is
going to be uh applied to your specific
coding workflow, right? Cuz if you're
working on a team on a production
project and if you're sharing the rules
with your entire team, you you can't
enforce your coding standard to someone
else, which is why you kind of have this
user rules. So um that's why those uh
common u scenarios can go into user
rules and that's what I have here. This
is my own personal coding standard or
coding ster I like. Uh so all of those
are just going into my user rules here.
So that's the first thing. So every
single um chat thread will have this
user rule. So for example if I just ask
her sir can you tell me what rules do I
have um in this project? Uh what are the
user rules?
Um, I'm going to [sighs] hit composer
one. It's really fast. It's going to
save me some time,
right? Um, so as you can see, uh, all
these rules are here. I I could just say
like, you know, keep it as is, don't
summarize. Uh but as you can see it
doesn't have anything in the uh project
but it it still has all the files
meaning that cursor by default injects
all of these rules into every single
chat request that you're sending to um
cursor. Um so this is the first thing
you need to be a aware of because that
does make a day and night difference in
how your outputs look like with cursor.
Um and then um then let's let's talk
about project rules. Right. So here I'm
going to create a single rule file
called um test.m MDC.
Um it's going to be always applied. Um
the UI is kind of really hard to work
with because of the zoom but
um okay so here um I'm going to create a
random rule. Um,
so I'm going to say
always end your responses with a smiley
face and the phrase Iron Man.
I want to say Iron Man.
And the reason I say Iron Man here uh is
because I want it to be obvious that it
actually is, you know, applying my rules
correctly. And just to show you guys how
the different rules play into, uh,
effect. So I can just say hi here now
and it should in theory reply with end
the response with parent man but since
um we are using composer it's not really
good at following the instructions I'll
probably switch to 4.5 set and you'll
see that it's actually gets applied.
Okay. Uh what's going on here? Um,
this is always I've not I didn't save
it. That's why. Um,
H.
All right. I don't know why it's not
working. Let me let me Is it even
applying the rule to the context?
There seems to be a bug here.
I've done this hundreds of times and it
works every single time. I don't know
what's happening today. Um
with uh
it's iron man.
Um
what's the weather?
>> [snorts]
>> Oh, my bad. I did not create the file
under the rules directory. That's why it
was not applying.
Now, if I just say simple hi,
excuse me. So, are you just using
built-in cursor chat or is that client
you're using?
>> It's a built-in cursor chat. I could
disable client and all the other things.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah. So, this is cursor. Uh, it's not
client. Um, there's definitely something
going on. Um,
>> true. What is it true?
>> Um, I think I might have changed it, but
yeah.
So if I just say hi, it should in theory
work. Uh let me it it is under the rules
directory. So it should work this time.
Yeah, it worked. Um
live demos are always tricky. Uh but
yeah, so it always apply apply
intelligently. So here I could say
>> [snorts]
>> um
um so here you could basically like
apply this rule when a certain condition
happens. So for example like um I want
to apply this rule whenever um uh the
user is greeting me. Um so I could say
um use this rule whenever the user is
gre greeting you but do not apply this
rule in all the other scenarios.
Um and in production like you can you
know apply you can think of like cloud
skills for example like in cloud skills
you can say like hey if you're working
with a presentation file or excel file
then only you apply this rule. So
similar thing in cursor as well. So this
is cursor equivalent of clot skills if
you're aware of cloud skills. Um but
basically here I'm I'm greeting it. So
it should reply uh and it should apply
this rule um and end the response with
iron man
did um so it basically exploded the file
because I greeted it right now. Now if I
end the response with iron man and I'm
not going to have this file in the
context cuz if it's open it's going to
be in the context and it's going to end
with iron man. So I could say what's the
weather
and here I'm not greeting so it should
not um it should not end the response
with iron man. This is a very basic
foundation before I get started because
otherwise it's going to be hard for me
to explain the rest of the session.
All right so it worked. Um the third
type of rule is apply to specific files.
So here I'm just going to say star.tsx
tsx
right um
save so now if I say hi
it's this rule is not going to be
applied unless a tsx file is in the
context so I could create a sample tsx
file
right um say pass
don't do anything
Um
and then
cursor used to have this um context
ring here that you used to show like
what's in the context but I think they
removed it in the recent versions. Um
they're working on a newer version of it
but yeah um and now if I just say hi
again
it should be applied because now the tsx
file is in the context. So that I think
this is the foundation of how the rules
work in cursor and then if you have
multiple modules you can have you know
multiple rules in all those all of those
different modules and those will be
applied and those rules can also be
treated as memory as well if you want
to. Um so yeah it did end the response
with iron man because now the tsx file
is in the context. Okay so that's the
basics about rules. So now let's get
back to the slides and um move on to the
next section. Um
all right. Um so
feel free to use your own project if you
have. If not uh you can uh clone this
repository in your local um
you don't have to clone this repository.
You can also you know work on any of
your own project if you want to. But if
you don't have anything to work on, you
can clone this repository. And that's
what I'm going to be using.
I could also just paste this uh that
link in the Zoom chat. Um
>> just past Discord. I'll put it in Zoom
as well.
>> Yeah, let me just do that.
>> Just a practical question. Um does this
assume that we have a paid cursor
account or no?
Um,
I think you can use the free one as
well, uh, with the auto mode and that
should work just fine. If you have a
paid version, that's going to be much
better. But, uh, if you have a free one,
that's, uh, fine as well. You can also
just use your own API key. If you don't
have the paid account, just like grab an
open AI key or entropy key and just put
that in and that should also do the
trick.
Um
yeah, if you don't know, you can
basically just uh
so if you go to the models tab and then
if you go to API keys, you can bring
your own keys and that way you don't
have to pay for cursor. Um
so that's one way to get started. Um
okay. So now um
present again.
All right. Um so before we actually get
hands-on into testing, we need to
understand uh some of the new cursor 2.0
features that we are going to use to um
to power our workflows. Um so [snorts]
cursor 2.0 released um uh composer 1
which is their state-of-the-art model
for AI coding which is um fine-tuned for
EI coding. Um and then they also
released workers meaning that you can
use uh you can invoke multiple models
for the same prompt and they all work in
parallel to get a job done. Um so that's
going to make your workflows really
really fast. So I'll show a demo of that
how we can implement that. Um they also
uh introduced built-in browser and play
at MCP which will allow us to kind of um
work directly inside of cursor for front
end and kind of uh use play MCP for
testing and web automation as well. And
they also introduce hooks uh which I use
a lot for um for applying reinforcement
learning techniques to my cursor
workflows. So treating the cursor
workflows same as your agents uh and
applying re re infusement learning
techniques on top of your cursor
workflows as well. Um treating them same
as the agents. Um so um let's actually
show quick um quick um demo of composer
one varies and then playright as well.
Um so I'll switch over to cursor. Um
[snorts] okay so just to give you guys
some idea let me first run this app.
So this is the app that um I wanted to
demo today. So this is something that I
built to share the cursor resources or
you know the rules and MCPS and stuff
like that uh that I've been collecting
over the years um collecting and
building myself. Um you know it has a
lot of rules and commands that you can
use to um uh use to work faster and be
more productive in cursor. Um and you
can just click on whatever you would
like and it it should add that to your
cursor as well. Um so that's the app
that we are working with. Now as you can
see there's no easy way to share the
resource. So I want to add a sharing
link. Um simple you know feature that I
want to develop in this application. Um
so let let me actually open cursor and
actually let's start to implement that
um using multiple models. Um, so let's
say I want to implement this using four
models. I want to, you know, run with
composer 1. And by the way, Google just
released Gemini 3.0 like an hour ago. So
I'm going to use that um and um set 4.5.
So I I want to implement this feature
with all these three models at the same
time and then see the output of each
model in real time and see how how well
each model did. um kind of good test for
um for uh Geminina 3 here as well. Uh
gonna make composer one just one um use
multiple models. So one with one time
with composer one, one time with
Geminina 3 and one time with plots onet
4.5. Um and then let me paste the
feature that I wanted to work on. Um
um yeah. Okay. So the prompt just says
implement a resource sharing feature and
keep testing until it works. So here I'm
doing two things. Um I'm I'm asking you
to implement a resource sharing feature
and I I'm also asking you to keep
testing it until it works. Um here I
have not defined strict requirements.
Ideally, I would, you know, create a
markdown document with the plan and the
spec, but for the sake of this demo. I
don't want to stretch it stretch it too
long, so I'm just going to keep it
simple. Um, so here I'm simply saying
keep testing it until it works. Um, so
it's going to define its own acceptance
criteria. I could define my own, but for
the sake of this demo, I'm just going to
let the model do that. And then test
both the back end and front end if
needed. Use the Chrome Dev Tools and
play at MCP for testing your own work.
And then I'm going to do add browser. Um
um
they removed it again. Okay. Um
yeah, they they removed add browser. So
probably I'm going to rely on the model
to do that. I'm going to enable Chrome
DevTools MCP. Um
um you can um grab the Chrome D MCP from
either the cursor um uh marketplace or
you can also just go to my app that I
just shared and uh get it from there. So
there's also a link. I'm going to copy
the link address and also share that in
the Zoom chat. So this is a deployed
version. It's not like really deployed.
It's just working in production.
Um yeah um you can grab that to to grab
all the MCP servers and all the
resources that I'm going to be sharing.
Um so I have chromed MCP server and
playrite just comes with cursor. So if
you if you go over here and go to tools
as you can see um playright is
configured here. When you see browser
when you see browser automation here
it's just simply play mcp. Um so I have
play mcp and I have chrome dev tools. So
I'm just asking it to use Chrome Dev
Tools and play at MCP to test its own
work. And now uh I have three models
here. Um so I'm going to 3X
uh Gemin 3.5 Pro. There's a bug here.
Now I'm selecting three models and it's
it's showing four. Anyway, um I'm going
to hit send. So this should create um
fail to create kit work tree.
What's going on?
So it cancelled the task in all the
other workies which is weird. There's a
bug going on here. Um,
so I'm going to say models. Um, for the
sake of this, I'm just going to keep two
models. Um,
what's going on?
I'm going to ask to fix this. I don't
have time to debug myself, so I'm just
going to say fix this.
[snorts]
Except
I'm just going to say
Just remove that hook.
All right. So, that's removed. So, now
it should work. Um,
sorry. Uh
agents editor mode
chat
then select multiple models
composer and sonet 4.5 only one times
composer.
Let's actually just comment this
move.
All right. And then
so this should uh run two models in
parallel as you can see. Sonnet 4.5 and
composer one um
side by side.
So compressor one is actually already uh
doing a lot of work already.
Sonet is still figuring out
It's going to take about 2 minutes for
it to be done.
All right. So now it started testing.
I think the app is not running.
So it's run that now.
And now it's starting to test its own
work.
And actually, let's actually see what's
going on.
So, this is the highle overview of how
how that works. I don't think we can
keep waiting for it to finish the entire
testing work cuz that's probably going
to take 15 to 20 minutes. Um, but as you
can see, it would take take a snapshot
of the page. Take a screenshot if needed
as well. Um, it's not taking a
screenshot yet. Um, just trying to
probably figure out the elements.
It's listing console message to see
what's going on inside. Um,
it's probably stuck here, I think.
>> Ask a question.
>> Yep.
>> Uh, does it have to have the browser in
the foreground like in front of
everything to be able to take a
screenshot or can this all just happen
in the background? Could I run this
automated in the cloud somewhere?
Um so right now the background agents in
cursor do not have access to MCP
servers. Um so I don't think you can uh
you know uh do it. Um you can actually
use browser based MCP. It it does have
um remote execution but it'll be your
own custom workflow. It will probably be
not something that you can just do out
of the box. You can set up your own um
Docker file for the background agent
that can include everything that you
want and then that background agent will
have access to MCP server. It it can
work that way but out of the box it
doesn't support that. If you want your
custom workflow you have to build your
own docker image to do that basically.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Yep. Um so it's taking a screenshot to
see what's happening. Um,
sun is still working. It's not done
implementing. Um, composer one is done.
It's testing. Um, and then let's say
let's assume that the testing went well.
Uh, we we're probably not going to have
time to go through the entire testing
ourselves right now. So, I'm going to
stop this. But let's say you are happy
with the changes and you want to now
apply all of this or bring all of this
to your actual main branch. So you can
apply all of this and that will bring
all of the changes in your um in your
local branch, right? Um and then you can
actually see how it's going to work in
your actual um uh application. So you
can run this again.
Is it running on 3000? Yeah.
Um it's getting some errors. You can
probably fix that. That's not an issue.
Um yeah so we're not testing this part
so it's probably fine um it's very small
u bug um uh but can be fixed so you can
that's how you can bring the issue bring
the changes from uh one git vector to
your current branch and then you can
undo apply and let's say I I want I
really like sonet 4.5 changes I could
probably apply do apply here and then
it's going to basically apply sonet 4.5
changes into my branch now. Um so if I
now um go back to local 3000 as you can
see um cloud for actually did a good job
um at implementing that and the share
feature is there you can um say it's
going to expire in like one and then
it's going to yeah I'm not authenticator
right now so it's not working but that's
not the point uh the point is like you
can actually see the changes from both
the models at the same time so I did not
have to like ask composer one to fix it
changes cuz I I ran two models, one 4.5,
one composer one. One of them did a
really good job at implementing my
feature. It worked out of the box. Saved
me time of you know going back and
fixing it. It just worked. So that's how
you can bring bring changes from one G
work tree to the other and just make
sure that it just works. Or you can also
just ask the agent to combine both the
changes and take the best of them and
just uh uh you know merge all of those
into your um your actual branch. So I'm
going to undo all of this as well. I'm
don't want to have all of this. So I'm
going to discard all the files.
Okay. Um so that's how the composer one
and get workies with multimodel works in
cursor. Now so that's a new feature that
the cursor released in cursor 2.0. We
also saw the agents invoking playright
MCP to test to try to test it own work.
And the last thing I wanted to show was
hooks. Um so
there is plenty of ways you can use
hooks. Um the way I use it is actually
um
uh in production. uh what I do is I
use this hooks to create CSV files out
of the input and output that I'm getting
from the models and then I take a few
samples collect few examples of the
specific workflow and then apply
reinforcement learning technique using
DSPI to improve my prompts to get to
what I want so that you have
deterministic workflows. Um, but as you
can see, I have this audit hook that
basically um, literally just takes the
JSON input and then just writes all of
that into this agent audit log file. So
everything that I'm doing is being
logged somewhere. So this is really
useful for enterprises looking to figure
out like how their developers are using
um, cursor. Um, u, but you can use write
a hook to do almost anything using a
shell script. Um um and then if I
actually open my cursor folder, it
should be able to also show you guys the
audit log. Um yeah, so that's the log
file. So it has all the logs um
everything that I did in cursor um right
here. Um so you can use this in multiple
different ways like I mentioned um and
or or you can write your own hook uh to
do something. Um you can also write a
hook to automatically optimize your
prompts before it gets to the model. Um
so yeah um
okay so that's about cursor hooks now
let's move on to the next uh section
all right so now I think uh we can talk
about uh testing the AI generated code
um so how do you test uh you know the
code while um the agent is doing it
right I I think I showed a a quick demo
of that you can just ask the model to
test its own to test its own changes
while it's doing it right. Um you can
also make it part of implementation
plan. So normally I do not give it ad
hoc prompts like this. I would have
actually a statement of work that would
actually uh dictate what acceptance
criteria it needs to have how to test
the changes and stuff like that and that
would result in a much more coherent
response. U so um so you can ask the
model to test its own changes uh make it
part of your plan as well. So when
you're giving the prompt ask the model
to to test its own changes and if you
have some scenarios in mind you can also
just make it part of your prompt um
during implementation um so that you
don't have to ask the model to test its
own changes afterwards or fix itself
afterwards as it can just see um its
failures and kind of fix itself while
it's doing it. Um and then you can also
test it after building. So I I use this
uh MCP server called test sprite. Uh and
along with that I also use Chrome
DevTools to test the changes after uh
building um and uh uh you know I have
also made this reusable workflow and I
then uh you know reference it as a rule
as well so that you can invoke the
workflow as a rule after it's done. So
I'm also going to show an example of
that as well. And then the standard way
of testing is also writing unit test. I
think all the devs know that already.
I'm not going to talk about that a lot,
but um let's actually see how you can uh
use um uh test sprite to test the
changes after it's done. Um um so
I have a few changes that I worked on.
Um
um so I'm going to apply the changes
here.
All right. So I've got quite a few
changes here. Um let's say I did not
write let the agent write this code. Um
I wrote this code myself and now I want
to test these changes. Make sure that it
actually aligns with my product
requirement documents and everything. Um
so for this sake of this I'm going to
use a tool called test sprite.
Um I'm going to enable test sprite.
So I have seven tools. Um
and then I want to give the agent some
context. So I'm going to say um
summarize all the stage changes in the
current repository um and uh format them
in markdown
staged changes.
So by default cursor also um whenever
the request is relevant cursor is also
going to put pull in the g changes
automatically. So you don't have to like
provide the g diff to the agent. The
agent kind of already knows unless like
you you explicitly ask it. Then the
agent is actually going to you know run
the command and actually get the current
diff. Um,
by the way, you should not run
everything all the time. I'm just doing
it for the sake of this demo to to make
things faster. Um,
What's going on here?
All right. So now we have the summary of
all of the changes.
You see this context ring here? Uh you
can actually see the active rules here.
Um I'm not sure what's going on but I
was not seeing this context string
earlier and now I'm seeing it. Um so you
can actually see all the rules that are
being applied in this session already.
Um so we have the TypeScript rule that
being that's being applied. We have
sneak rules and then we have commenting
standards um rule that is being applied
to this uh chat session right now. Um
anyway now we have all of this. Um, so I
created a workflow for testing the the
changes with test sprite. Um,
um,
yeah. So I created this workflow that
basically um, bootstraps the entire
testing environment for test sprite. Um,
and we're also going to see how to
create re reusable workflows like this
um, in this session as well. So
basically I have this workflow that that
defines how to test the current changes
with test sprite. Um so I'm I'm I'm
going to invoke this workflow. Um so I'm
just going to do slash and test
application with test sprite and then
also have a prd file that defines what
is this product and then I'm just going
to say to say test the current changes
with testright.
Let me make sure that the MCP tools are
enabled.
um
test sprite
and then if I hit enter
if you guys have any questions
questions, feel free to ask them now.
Um, the agent is probably going to take
5 [clears throat] minutes to run.
>> Any questions at all about cursor its
use?
>> Yeah.
>> Is there other open-source tools for
testing?
>> Open-source tools for testing. I would
say like you can use Playright MCP for
testing. That's one of the open source
ones. Um, you can build re reusable
workflows for playright as well. I can
probably show that if uh folks are
interested in doing that. I can uh just
show that. But um other than that like
there's no like you know a full-blown
application uh that's available uh to
test changes like yeah that's open
sourced. There's nothing. Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> Um
>> sounds like an opportunity for someone
to write one uh you want to pick that
up. Any other questions at all?
>> Password for S6. Sorry.
>> Yeah. Hi. Um I've noticed that there's a
feature where you can have multiple
agents um running on one particular
query like you um well sorry not agents
LLMs like you can have Gemini um Gemini
claude
um you know open AAI whatever right
what's the usefulness of that like how
can we get the best usage out of that
>> um if I'm understanding your question
correctly you're asking if uh you can
use multiple different models
um to run agents in parallel and then
like what's the use case of that
um so like I mentioned um you can use
that uh to
uh implement an feature in parallel
right so for example like all the
different models have different
strengths right so for example like
u composer one is really good at you
know creating front-end code cloud 4.5
is really good at creating front-end
code right um and sometimes you you
know, you might just want to use cloud
4.5 like four times to see like uh what
what kind of different designs it comes
up with, right? Or um if you're working
on an architecture solution, um you want
to see kind of um um
you want to like run that with different
models to see what kind of different
architecture patterns it come up with to
to help you brainstorm as well, right?
So you can run the same model with like
same prompt with four different models
to help with debugging. That's how I use
it. Like I I use like four or five
different models to debug an issue or to
to review my code. So I get a review
from Cloud 4.5 Sonnet. I I get a review
from Codeex. I I get a review from
Gemini and and then I see all those
reviews and see if I, you know, spot
anything interesting there. Or you could
combine all of them and then ask the
model to fix all those issues. So you
can use them in multiple different ways.
the like the possibilities are like
infinite. There's like you can almost do
anything with it, right? It's it's like
it's going to give you so much time back
when you're running those in parallel
cuz you're not not going to have to do
as much of back and forth to find those
issues or to implement those features.
Um
um so it's probably going to fail. I I'm
going to ask it to create a test user. U
but it's basically asking me to um to
select the scope of testing. So I want
the scope to be the git diff right now.
Um I want to test only the front end. Um
and then it's running on 3000. I'm going
to give it a PD file. So that's um
the PD file is right here. So I'm going
to give it the PD file. It understands
the codebase. Then I'm going to
continue.
Then if I go back
now, it got
um the PD. So it's probably going to
create a bunch of tests for me. Um,
if you guys want to see any other
feature in cursor or if you have any
other confusing question or anything,
I'm happy to answer that as well cuz
it's probably going to take a long time
for the agent to do the whole thing. Uh
so I normally use this time to take um
Q&A.
>> Any questions,
right? So it it actually creates a code
summary as well with the features with
the different features, the endpoints
and everything itself as well. Um
um yes please
go ahead.
Um so while it's doing that we can also
probably start start to uh form the
basis of um securing the code with AI um
in cursor. Um it's probably going to
take a long long time.
Um
all right. Um
so
while it's testing we can also kind of
talk about security. Um so how do you
secure AI generated code right? Um so
first is like
the best is like you know just create
secure code from scratch right so
prevention is always better than cure.
So use rules with OS standard or
whatever your standard is for security.
So use rules from this from the
beginning and those should be like
always applied uh so that like you
always u create secure code right so
there are tools that allow you to do
this efficiently but you can also create
your own rules and workflows for your
own uh project if you like to um there's
also a tool called corridor um I was
going to demo that today but I won't be
able to they're not they're probably
down because of the cloud player issue
um it's not working today but um what
does is that whenever you give it a
prompt, um it actually takes a look at
your prompt, see if there's an issue
with your prompt or like it's going to
rewrite your prompt uh to to make it
more secure so that the agents generate
secure code from scratch so that you
don't have to like try to fix it later
on. You just end up generating a secure
code from the beginning. Uh so that's
what it influences. So you can influence
how the agents write code from the
beginning. So that's how you you
generate secure code from the scratch.
So that's going to help you prevent
generating code with with issues and
vulner vulnerabilities. Um and then um
um the second part is you can also uh
secure the code after generating. I
think um sneak is a really good tool. Um
and then another one that I like is code
rabbit. Um so sneak has an MCP server.
So you can actually generate the code
and after that you can use sneak uh to
scan the generated code inside of your
agent. So I know that we have been using
sneak in GitHub for a long long time uh
right to to like um to scan the code for
issues but like what if you could just
make it part of your coding workflow
inside of cursor or inside of cloud code
whatever agent you're using so that
after it's generating the code it's also
going to use um sneak to scan your code
and fix itself before it actually goes
to GitHub. Um and then the second one is
code rabbit. Code Rebbit is a code
review tool, but uh it actually does
incorporate sneak inside of it. So if
you're actually using code rabbit, you
might actually not even need sneak
because it just has that inside of it. I
think um there is a really good resource
of um
u
yeah u
yeah so code rabbit has all of these
tools in built. So I think sneak is part
of that.
Um
yeah so it is git links OSB scanner
remnification and a lot of other uh
security tools here um
plenty of tools for security um
so if you're using um u you know yeah
sam grab is there as well um so I used
to use sam grab to also you know um scan
uh code for issues um security wise and
once I started using code rabbit all of
that just came with code rabbit so I
just like now use code rabbit for all of
that um um but yeah that's that's like
one way of uh of uh um making sure that
your gender code is secure and then like
obviously the standard scan uh the code
for issues using GitHub actions um um so
actually let's actually also try to
review some of the workflows that I have
created um While you do that, do you
mind if I I mention another tool uh
slightly self- serving because I made it
uh that is similar to that that middle
column like uh while you're uh while
you're writing scan for vulnerabilities.
There's a a tool called Gripe G R Y P.
It's fully open source vulnerability
scanner very similar to Sneak. And I
wrote an MCP server in Python so you can
have that as part of your development
process to have it scan for
vulnerabilities before you push to
GitHub. Um, it's on GitHub just for gr
MCP. Um, yeah, I just thought that might
be useful. It's fully open source, you
know.
>> Nice. I didn't know about that. Thank
you.
>> Yeah, I didn't write it that that long
ago. It's not been around very long.
Um but yeah, let's um getting back to
security. So basically, if you install
the sneak MCP, it's going to
automatically set up the sneak sneak
extension. It's also going to
automatically set up the sneak MCP for
you. And then it's also going to set up
the sneak rule in your cursor rules
directory. So right now the sneak rules
uh that says that always run the sneak
code scan tool um whenever the code is
generated and rescan after the code um
after fixing the issues to make sure
that there are no issues and then repeat
this process until new issues are found.
So it's kind of already doing it for you
just by installing the extension. So you
don't have to do anything extra for
that. Um and then um yeah um maybe I can
also start security in parallel. Um
so I have
>> [snorts]
>> um
yeah so I have this workflow that says
um
scan get changes with sneak. Let's
actually also see how we can create
similar workflows. Right? So, I'm just
going to say uh I'm just going to get
rid of this workflow for now. So, it's
not there.
Um,
can you scan the current git changes um
with sneak for security issues?
And I want this to be quick. I don't
want it to take too long. So, I'm just
going to use composer one. Um,
do I have sneak MCP enabled? I probably
disabled that which it's there. Okay.
Right. Um
so I have this this workflow called
create new workflow. Um
so this asks me um set of questions to
understand what I'm trying to get out of
a specific thing. So normally what I do
is uh whenever I'm working with cursor
and I see myself doing the same thing or
giving the same prompt or doing the same
task more than two to three times I run
that through this so that it creates
that a workflow for that and then I save
that into my cursor commands directory
so that I can just invoke that the next
time without writing the prompt myself
and the result of that I'm actually
going to get a lot more productive and
the results are going to be much more uh
accurate um and to the point. Um so um
it found three issues. Um it didn't fix
it automatically but now I can just say
uh you know uh create new workflow.
That's the workflow that I want. Create
a new workflow for sneak that will
automatically uh scan the current div
changes uh with sneak and um then it's
also going to automatically fix those as
well.
use the exit names of the sneak MCP uh
tool.
So it's important to also mention the
exact names of the tool. So every single
tool comes with you know different uh
tools. So here if you see it's
mentioning the exact tool name and the
reason of doing this is because it's
going to bring determination to the
workflows and make sure that it's also
going to call the exact tool that you
wanted to invoke every single time
without making a mistake. So if you go
here to the MCB section and if you hover
over uh the tool section actually let me
expand this and then you can actually
see uh the tool description and the args
and everything for the specific tool. So
you can actually use the exact same tool
name tool name in your workflows to uh
to make your workflows more
deterministic and then you can also in
future like I mentioned like apply
reinforcement learning techniques to
these workflows itself. So it does
exactly what you want, but that's going
to be a little bit of stretch. Um, so
yeah, I'm going to And then if I hit
enter, it's going to ask me a few
questions. If it has questions, uh, if
it has all the contexts from the thread,
then it's probably going to just create
the workflow. It's asking me a few
questions probably. Um, yeah. So it's
asking me the workflow name, it just
went ahead with it. Um, but now it's
just creating the workflow for me. Uh so
the best practice is like whenever you
are working with something and if you're
doing the same thing two to three times
just create a workflow out of that and
that's going to help you uh save a lot
of time next time. Um and then you
manually review the workflow to make
sure that it actually does what you
intend it to do. But normally if you
know that doesn't work like you refine
the workflow um according to your needs
or whatever it needs uh to fix. Uh so
you can do that uh afterwards. So that's
like how you can create workflow or
let's say um
I don't want this security issues to
happen ever again. So I I can just say I
can also create new rules. Um um so
rule generating agent. Yeah. So I also
have another you know prompt or command
that helps me generate the rules that
helps me generate cursor rules. So I'm
going to say help me generate front end
specific um security rules so that this
security issues never happen again and I
can just uh apply that rule always to um
all of my chats.
So now it's just going to create a rule
for front end. Um so that it's uh going
to be applied to all the chats all the
time so that every single time I'm I'm
generating or rewriting a specific piece
of code it is going to apply that and
then as a result of that it's going to
generate the secure code. Um or you
could also like make it apply
intelligently meaning that you can say
hey just create a rule for uh forms. So
whenever I'm working on forms this rule
should automatically be applied and as a
result of that when whenever the agent
is creating new forms whenever is
writing new forms on TypeScript it's
going to apply this rule automatically
and then it's going to create secure
code as a result of that. So you don't
have to go ahead and go do back and
forth and fix it fix it with sneak or
any other tool. So that helps me save a
lot of time as well. Um so now I can
actually see that this rule is always
applied. Um and then it has all the
rules uh um that that allow the agent to
avoid these issues in the future when
generating similar code. Um right um so
it found the issues and it it gave
examples and all of that and now I have
a rule that I I can apply to generate
secure code. Um all right. Um let's see
where this is going. I think it's still
running. So, if I open test sprite, I
might be able to see what's going on.
All right.
Yeah, all the tests are in progress
still.
>> Can I ask a question?
>> Yeah. So, I noticed when you're using um
curset, you talk to it. You use your
voice. And I know a lot of people when
they're using like chatbt, they'll talk
to it like it's a person kind of thing.
Is that a thing you're specifically
doing today or do you always talk to
your uh agent like that rather than
typing?
>> I I barely type. I always talk cuz when
I'm talking I can give it more relevant
context. I can, you know, add more
things to the context and that really
helps the agent understand my task. So I
yeah, I almost never type anything. I
just talk.
>> Amazes me the little things you pick up
here. Am I alone? I never talk to my
agents. You don't or do like I can
understand from an accessibility point
of view. Like if typing is hard, but
that's blown my mind. So thank you for
that. Yeah, I actually have a list of
all the open-source tools that available
that you can use. So, I'm using Whisper
Flow, but I think there's plenty of apps
you can actually use to um I think
there's like voice sync that I used to
use. Um there's also like yeah, I forgot
the other one. Whisper real time is
something that I used to use as well.
So, you can use all all these tools to
just like u run text in real time in
your local um and do it as as well. But
yeah,
cursor also has inbuilt voice mode um
that you can use. I think it's command
shift um I forgot the exit command
because I've never used it. Uh
yeah, it's command shift V. Hey, is it
working?
Oops.
I could just actually voice.
Yeah, total vers is actually shift
command space. So shift command space or
is it shift control?
So it's shift command space. Yeah. So if
I do shift command and space
I can just talk whatever I want and
cursor should be able to.
Yeah. Okay. I hear you. Stop.
Yeah. So that works. I think test sprite
is still working on the changes on on
the test. It usually does not take this
painfully long. Um not sure why it's
taking so long, but as you can see
earlier, I ran the same test. Uh and um
some of them pass, some of them failed.
I could actually also see um the the
test that it was doing, what it was
doing for each test and how it worked.
Um,
so there might be something going on.
Maybe because of Cloudflare they're
down. I'm not exactly sure, but it's not
running. I think it's just getting
stuck. I'm not seeing anything here. So
there might be that infrastructure is
down, but you can see from the history
here that um uh yeah, we can actually
run the tests using test fight and it
will actually see give you a report. Um,
it's supposed to work. I hate live
demos. Um when when this happens
ah it's just stuck here.
Um so normally what this will do is it's
going to run the tests and it's going to
give me a report in the end and it's
also going to fix all the issues that it
finds in the test itself. Um
um but it's not working right now. So
I'm probably going to cancel that and
not going to wait on that for more than
a few minutes. Um, maybe I can ask the
model to use um
use playright to test the changes. Um,
cuz I wanted to show this workflow, but
it's somehow just stuck there. Um,
yeah, it's
all right. um
use playrite and chrome dev tools mcp um
to test all of your changes. Make sure
that um all of the acceptance criteria
is met. Um you can define your own
acceptance criteria for this scenario. I
don't have one. Uh but make sure that it
works as expected.
The agent generated this code. So there
might be some issues. So make sure that
you take screenshots and uh click on the
buttons and everything to make sure that
um all the functionality that we just
implemented is working
implemented.
All right. Um
yeah so we generated a security rule on
the security side um to make sure that
um you know it generates secure code all
the time. Um we also created a workflow
that helps us uh you know create uh more
workflows and if you go on the same
same application that I shared earlier
you can actually let me just go back
don't need to
You can actually scan for that as well.
So create
new
new workflow. So you can actually grab
that workflow from here. If you want to
get the rule, you can also just um
yeah grab the rule generic agent from
here as well and then apply that to your
own workflows. So um one advice that I
give to everyone is that like the only
way you're going to be more productive
is if you're automating your work.
Anything that you're doing repetitively
on a daily basis, just automate that. So
for example, I have um you know a
workflow for addressing PR review
commands. I have a workflow for um
automatically reviewing the generated
code and apply the changes with code
rabbit. I have a workflow for uh review
the changes with code rep with uh
cursorless bugbot. Um I have a workflow
that allows me to take current changes
and create a linear ticket out of that.
Create a branch, put that branch on
GitHub, create a pull request out of
that. Uh feel free to read any of these
workflows on the resource that I shared.
Um it's all there so you can um you know
be more detailed and review all of that.
But basically it's going to allow you to
uh commit changes to linear and sorry
commit changes to GitHub create a linear
to get out of that um create a pull
request out of that create a pull
request summary and communicate all of
that back to the linear or Jira as well.
Uh so that's going to save you a lot of
time. Um this feature documentation is
basically my memory agent. So I I use
this to create memory for a specific
model so that the agents uh can
understand what the specific model is
doing. if you're working on a humongous
codebase um and then a lot of other
workflows like merge resolver review get
right um and then I have this customized
rules for this project so if you happen
to copy one of the rules that I generate
um um or if you shared and then you want
to customize those all of those rules
for your for your own project you can
just run this workflow it's going to go
through your context of the project and
customize those for your project so that
it is relevant to your project and not
just something that is uh available out
there right so um so yeah um I would
suggest everyone to create their own
workflows if you're doing it if if
you're following the session feel free
to do that now and um try to run that
again to see how well that works and
hopefully that will help you move faster
uh in production applications um but
yeah um
let's actually see the agent testing so
yeah you can use.
Um, so now it's going through everything
and making sure that uh the search is
working beautifully. Um, it's making
sure that the breadcrumb navigation
works, the filters button works. This
doesn't necessarily mean that it's going
to be foolproof, but it actually is
going to save you a lot of time uh when
you are, you know, reviewing the PR. So
if a colleague is uh you know reviewing
your it's going to save them so much
time because um your code is going to
just end up being a lot more secure. So
um it tested that everything works. If
something didn't work it would also
automatically fix its own u mistakes. Um
but yeah so so that's how I would go
about testing um giving the model the
necessary tools to understand how your
end to end stack flows. There's also
Sentry MCP server, Langmith MCP server,
observe MCP server. So whatever tools
you're using, it has it probably has an
MCP server. You can give the models all
those tools so that the model can
actually have the full picture of your
CFD pipeline and everything and kind of
it can fix itself whenever it makes a
mistake. Um, so that's how you move
really really fast. Um, I'm going to
stop it here because I think the testing
is done, but it's just creating a
summary. And as I mentioned, I had a
strict rule that says do do not create
markdown files because I didn't want the
models to use all these tokens to create
a summary document, but
it just creates a text file. Now, um
yeah. Um
anyway, um so that's that's the testing
front. Um I'm going to stop the agent.
We already saw how we can, you know, um
apply security rules and um generate
secure code. So for example, if I was
generating this again, I would actually
use the rule that I created right here.
Um if I was working on um a new feature,
new new front end feature, I probably
just apply this security rule so that it
actually generates a secure code and as
a result of that, we're going to have
less issues. Um okay, so all of this is
great, but I'm pretty sure that even
after scanning all of this, um and
testing all of this, it still has a ton
of issues. It's not production ready
yet, right? it's uh so how do we um make
sure that the code is reviewed properly
the the the code um doesn't have any
issues right so that's where code rabbit
comes in
um I'm sure many of you are already
aware of code rabbit so I have actually
tested a lot of um
lot of tools to um
to review the code. Um,
let me see what is the
link this.
Yeah. So, if I open pull request and I'm
showing you guys because I wanted to
understand I wanted to show you guys the
strengths of different code review AI
code review tools that are available.
None of them are perfect. But what I
really like about Code Rabbit is because
of the the tools there is access to,
right? So that's a strength of code
because it can scan your code from
multiple different angles from all these
different tools. Um and as a result of
that it's it generally like you know um
uh finds the issues much much better. So
this is the same changes that I have in
my local but just created a pull request
for that and and then as you can see I
did not create anything. All of this is
generated by code rabbit. It's it's now
giving me a summary of all the changes
what's implemented what file and it's
also giving me a sequence diagram so I
can easily understand uh what's
happening in this specific pull request.
Um
um and then if you go down it's also
giving me code code walkthrough of
what's exactly happening. So it's going
to make
pull requests really really reviewing
the pull requests really really easily.
So one of the challenges in my org is
that like uh we did all of these cursor
sessions to figure out how to write code
more securely, how to test it properly.
As a result of that, we are generating
code extremely fast. As a team of I
think eight devs, we opening like more
than um 100 PRs in a week. Um so we're
generating code extremely fast. But
reviewing that is really painful cuz
generating code is really easy. But like
with all these tools, but you still have
to manually, you know, uh review every
single PR to make sure that nothing goes
bad in production. Um and then uh you
know, a lot of issues can just be there
in um the peers. So by incorporating all
these tools into the workflow, you're
just making your job as a peer reviewer
a lot more easier. Uh and as you all
know, like the coding agents are working
really really well these days and
they're improving day by day. Um so I
think probably in the next two to three
years like we we will be writing a lot
less code but we will be reviewing a lot
of code because you can't just let
anything go to production right uh so
that's where these workflows are really
really helpful and understanding the
strengths of each of these tool really
helps you move faster and
um approve the peers faster as well. Um
so um so we already saw that I think
this is all so generated by code rabbit.
Um and then if you go down um it's also
showing me what are the effects and
stuff. I have another tool configured
code. Um that's also telling me uh the
test coverage. So it's not only telling
me so because I have this code cover
inside of it as well. It's now telling
me if there's any test missing for a
specific module in the code. And as you
can see, I have really bad code
coverage. So I need to add that. So this
is also highlighting that. Um I also
have Graptile. One thing I like about
Grappile is that Gravile is another code
review tool. The reason I have Graptile
configured here is because Graile
uh allows me to uh let me open Graile
here. Uh
so Gravile also uh includes your cursor
rules um inside of the review. So it's
it's not just like using random tools,
but it's also um
um
maybe I am
where where did my connections go?
Yeah.
Yeah, custom context. So, as you can see
here, all of my cursor rules are also
part of the code review um in Gravile.
So, um that's how that's why I love
Grapile because it also uh you know
takes another angle and um reviews the
code with my own standards, not just
something that's uh defined in the
tools. So, that's why I have Grapile. It
also kind of figures out what I like
versus what I don't like. and um gives
me that command. And yeah, as you can
see, code rabbit found quite quite a lot
of issues here. All of this could have
been avoided if I ran
a workflow inside of it that will help
me um
um
help me fix all of these issues right
inside the ID without actually creating
a pull request. Cuz if I did it without
that, whoever is reviewing the code will
have a hard time figuring out what's
changed. and then the result of that
they probably end up spending two to
three hours just reviewing my PR and
it's going to waste a lot of time and
slow us down. So which is why having
these tools inside of the IDE and fixing
issues before they go to PR will so will
save you a ton of time. Um so I I just
have this workflow. I just invoke that
and it's now taking um all of my changes
and um you know it's going to fix the
genius as well. So it's analyzing is
probably going to find the same issues
that it found earlier. One more thing is
cursor also released their own agent
review. So it didn't find any issues yet
but I could also um start the start
start the review process here. Um and
this actually can run uh on commit. Um
so I believe that
uh let me open the settings here. Yeah.
So you can start the agent review on
commit. So every single time you commit
something, it can automatically start
the review and this yeah you can
configure how it works. But um that's
one way to kind of make sure that uh
your review works really well. Um and
then if you have a pro pro account in
cursor you can also configure bugbot. Um
I personally like code raid which is why
I'm not using cursor as bugbot. But uh
if you have cursor bugbot you can also
uh define your bugbot rules like this
simple bugbot. MD file in the root of
cursor and you can also kind of nest
that as well so that every single time
uh it's in a specific module that's
going to take precedence. So you can
have um
so you can have um a bugboard.md in in
your front end module. You can have
bugboard.md in your back end in your
infra and then it's going to take that
bug file uh in in the context when it's
reviewing the bugbot locally and also uh
on your ps when you run run it through
cursor bugbot. Um so that's that's one
thing um to note as well. Um and um yeah
um I think we already
um any questions from the audience at
all?
Everyone's still alive out there. Good.
>> I have a question.
>> Yeah.
>> So, uh I have two questions. One, um
you've been editing a lot of rules and
uh
If you've been uh maintaining one
project, right? It might have lots of
modules, front end, back end, lots of
bits and pieces. If you have lots of
different projects,
do you use the same set of rules or do
you iterate on them and have a
completely new set for the new project
and iterate on them and have a new set
for the new project and then as you go
on, do you end up with projects that are
have legacy like rules in them and you
have to maintain? maintaining the rules
is as much of a work as maintaining the
code.
>> Yeah, really great question. Um, and I
think this is one of the hardest
problems to solve like especially like
when you're working on a codebase or
with a team of like I don't know 100 200
devs, right? Cuz every single person has
their own workflow and um they're
probably working on different projects.
So how do you make sure that the rules
that you have are are relevant for all
the projects right? So I start with the
basic which is what I have. So I'll take
all the rules and then I also have a
rule for that or I I also have a command
that helps me customize the rules for
that specific project. So I I think I
showed this earlier as well that I have
this this rule that's going to ask me a
few questions to understand uh what I
want to do or what I want to customize
for that specific project. So it's also
going to you know go through the
codebase understand what's happening in
the specific project and then it's going
to ask me a few questions. Hey this is
what I'm noticing. Do you still want to
you know um uh use this rule or change
this in a little bit different manner
stuff like that right? Um and then I
have workflows for example this linear
workflow right um um this linear
workflow where I'm literally mentioning
the the ticket style like AIC XXX right
so AIC is the code of the project on
linear so if you're working on a
different project the code is going to
be different right so you need to modify
all these tools for your new project
right so you can take a baseline and
then you can basically run that agent
that that's going to take all of that
content text and um customize those for
that new project. And I would suggest
using a model like CLET. So I could
literally just like you know shove the
entire folder into the context and then
it can iterate on that cuz it
understands what rules I have right now
and what needs to update for the current
project. Um
>> okay
sense
more maintenance but it's maintenance
that will accelerate you. Um my next
question was on um when you were looking
at GitHub I think it was code rabbit you
said that code rabbit can also have your
cursor rules in there and review your
cursor rules. Was it code rabbit doing
that or some other tool doing that?
>> Review your cursor rules or was it
>> that was grapile.
>> Which one was that?
>> Grapile. Um
>> did I Yeah, here.
>> So it has custom context. Um, so you can
bring all of your cursor rules and you
know that's this is repository scoped.
So as you can see it's saying that for
this repository. So when it's going to
review this project it's going to apply
these rules when reviewing as well on
top of what it already has. So my
question is, and I think you've just
answered it, is it's reviewing the
codebase and making sure it complies
with the guidelines that are set out in
these custom rules. It's not reviewing
the rules, it's reviewing the code,
complies with them.
>> Yes.
>> Okay, now I understand. Thank you.
>> Any other questions? I I'm monopolizing
the questions here.
And yeah, just to be clear, like I treat
these rules as my own agents because
if you're not really testing your rules
or your workflows, then it just means
that you can't rely on these models to
produce something. So to bring that
determination, I think you need to like
test these rules and make sure that they
work as expected and keep tweaking them
until they work exactly as you ex as you
want them to. Yeah. Um
um [snorts]
yeah. So I think code rabbit is done
reviewing the code. It does take us take
a bit of time. So it found some issues
and it's trying to fix those. It's
asking me to edit the um get ignore. Um
so as you can see with just one command
without me writing any prompt or
anything it just figured out what it
needed to do and then it automatically
fixed all the issues. So so that when I
create the PI it doesn't have all of
those issues right or you can also just
mention your rule files here. So for
example, I have a rule file that says um
you know um
standards that says um no commands or
minimal commands. So you can also just
say make sure that make sure
this standard is followed.
The benefit of having all of these rules
and workflows is that if you share this
across your team, it's it's one thing to
like do this as an individual, but if
you want to apply this in your team and
if you share this with your team and if
your team collaborates on these tools
and if they use agents to write code,
all of the code is going to be really
standard. It's going to be really easy
to understand what's happening in the
entire codebase as a result of that
because everyone kind of follows the
same standard, same rules and the output
that you're getting is going to be
really really great and it'll be easy
for other people to understands each
other's work and really uh move fast as
a team. Um and it's also great for the
agents as well because they have to like
do less brainstorming to figure out
what's going on where. Um so yeah with
this workflow um I think it's able to
figure out um what was wrong and fix all
the issues and then I have another
workflow that I can probably use to let
me first create a linear ticket. Sorry,
linear MCP. Let me enable that. And the
reason I keep enabling and disabling all
these tools because if I had everything
enabled all at the same time, it's going
to pollute the context and I'm not going
to get good results if everything is
enabled. So, I'm probably going to have
to just keep working like this.
[snorts]
All right. So now I have linear. I also
need GitHub. Um
um so now let's say I want to take all
of these changes and commit this to my
GitHub. So I'm just going to enable
invoke the commit changes linear to
GitHub. And now it's going to create a
branch for this. I'm on main branch
right now. So I'm it's going to create a
branch for me. It's going to create a
linear ticket for me [snorts] and create
a pull request for me on GitHub and then
link that back to the to the linear
ticket as well for issue management. Um,
[clears throat]
right.
Um,
>> I have another question.
>> Yeah,
>> sorry. Uh, and I don't know if anyone
else can relate to this, but I have
certain projects that I contribute to. I
what you're doing and you're talking
about there's a lot of um a team working
on a project like you all know you're
heading in the same direction. You're
all using the same tools mostly using
the same rules, right? If you contribute
to a another project like an open source
project, there's sometimes some
reluctance to take contributions
that are obviously AI generated, right?
Um,
something I've used and I don't know how
ethical this is and I'd be interested to
hear people's point of view is I fed an
AI all of my written work and told it
write a pull request like I would write
it. And when I submitted that, it was
more successful at getting past people
who don't like AI because it was written
like I wrote it. Um, and I know that's
kind of cheating. Um, do you do you ever
get resistance to the these kind of like
tools outside of the sphere of your
organization or is that just not
>> um I'm not sure I fully understand your
question. Can you maybe rephrase a
little bit?
>> Boil it down to um do you ever have
reluctance from other people
>> taking AI generated code?
>> Yeah. Um almost all the time. Um
because developers, you know, like it
was hard for me to as well like to
change how I work or change, you know,
how I produce code cuz um yeah, I didn't
like the AI making so many mistakes and
stuff like that. But if I never started
doing this, I would have never improved.
Um so the way I tackle that is like
asking the developer, hey, like okay,
that's okay if you don't like it. what
it is that you hate doing on a daily
basis. What it is that you don't like
doing as part of your daily job, let's
first automate that. So that's how I get
them on board and I I have them create a
workflow that solves their problem. Once
they create a workflow that solves their
problem and saves them some some time
if they don't like doing that task for
me it was exactly this workflow commit
changes linear to GitHub because I work
at a startup. So sometimes, you know, I
don't have a specific ticket to work on.
I'm just told, hey, this is an issue. We
just have to fix. So I'm on a main
branch. I just work on the fix. The fix
is there. I don't want to go to Jira and
create a ticket, go to GitHub and put
the PR summary, review the code, all of
that's painful, right? For me at least.
Um so I created this workflow that
literally just takes my commit takes my
current changes that I would have
implemented and then creates a linear
ticket for that and it basically just
creates a pull request for that as well
and saves me so much time. So that's how
I get the developers on board once they
start using it because now now they have
a workflow and they're using it in
cursor or cloud core they're going to
start to do it more and more and I think
that's how they they will eventually see
the value of AI generated code and
that's how they will start using it and
that was one of the biggest challenge
that I had to solve at my or because
people didn't want to use cursor code
they didn't trust it
>> brilliant thank
Composer [snorts]
one is really not great at doing
anything other than coding. Um, let me
actually try Gemini 3 here.
Um,
incoming. So it now created an issue
RC6. So if I go back to my linear now, I
should see that issue here. Um
RC6, right?
It takes a while for linear to update.
So I'm just going to force it.
Yeah. So it's there. So I have the
linear issue now. Um it assigned that to
me as well. Um and um
It's really slow.
Yep. It so it created a new branch and
then it's um creating the commits for
that and in the end I think it's also
going to create the PR,
right? It It's Yeah.
[snorts]
It's also grouping all the changes
according to their usage and the
functionality. So which which uh creates
a really nice git commit history. I I I
would have probably just staged
everything all all at once and just
wrote a you know really shitty um commit
message, but doing it through the agent
is going to give you a lot more
flexibility and it's going to look much
better as a result of that.
>> Can I ask a question?
>> Yep.
>> Uh so what would you say are the main
differences between between uh Reptile,
Code Rabbit, and Bugbot. And how useful
do you think is having
like many tools reviewing your code?
>> Yeah, great question. So, um, Bugbot is,
you know, cursor's inbuilt, um, agent.
The main benefit of using Bugbot is that
it's, you know, it's part of the cursor
ecosystem. So if you're already using
cursor right you can uh use bugbot to
review your code. The additional benefit
that I think bugbot has is that it can
have module specific review rules. No
other tools give you that. So for
example I have this for example I don't
know this is rules directory where I
have have all the markdown files. Let's
say I wanted to have a rule here in this
directory for this specific module,
right? Or
I I want a rule for some other module
like back end and front end module. So
you can have your own custom bugbot um
MD file in that specific module and
that's going to be applied when the
agent starts to review the code um on
git. Right? So that's the main
difference. However,
the quality of the output or the issues
that it catches, it's not going to be as
great as Code Rabbit. I've tried uh
Graile. I've tried Graphite. I've tried
Code Rabbit. I've tried um
um Guitar. I've tried uh Cursus Bugbot.
I've tried to use my own cloud
extensions to review code um you know
with my own standard. So, I've tried all
these tools to figure out what gives me
the best review, right? what catches the
most issues like actual relevant issues
and not hallucinations and so far I've
just been impressed with code driver it
catches everything correctly there's
like less hallucinations
um cursor still sometimes catches issues
that are you know not really an issue
and just hallucination um so out of all
of that I used to use bugbot I'm not
using it anymore um I mainly use code
rabbit uh because it works really really
Well, and then I use Gravile as well. Um
because Graile also reviews the code
from my coding standard. So this is
something that I had to do manually
before meaning that once I generate the
code I had to like manually invoke the
command to make sure that hey did the
generated code follow my standards or
not and then if not it would fix that.
Um but you know um if you don't want to
do that I do that but let's like someone
in my team doesn't do that all the time.
So how do you make sure that they also
follow the same standard? So Grappile
will catch that. So if if you don't, you
know, follow the workflow that I've
defined to catch the issues, well,
you're going to be forced to do that.
Um, so Graile does that for you. Uh, so
that's the strength of Graile. Um, Core
Rabbit is just like really good
overalls. It catches the issues from
multiple different angles, which is what
I really really like. Um, so so I think
that's the strength of uh, code rabbit.
Um, I hope that that answers your
question.
Why is it keep just do it?
Geminina 3.3 Pro is seems to be really
um interactive. It it wants to ask me a
lot of questions before it does
anything. Sorry, I'm just trying this
live. I've never tried this model. It
just got released some an hour ago.
So, my tool is not working. Use CLI. I'm
just going to ask it to use the CLI. Um,
use cursor composite one.
And let's see what's what's left in the
presentation. I think after this is
done, we are done.
>> I have another question.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I noticed you switch models uh and
providers quite frequently like you
know, oh this one's a bit slow or that
one doesn't do what I want. Is that
common? Do you like not like stick with
one from the start to finish? you're
just like flip-flop or is that just the
environment that we're in that you're
doing that? Is that common thing?
>> Yeah. So I there's two things that I do
very frequently. One is like switching
on and off the MCP servers because if I
have everything enabled so for example
like for this specific task linear to
GitHub I only wanted linear and the G
MCP tool. And the reason is because if I
had everything else enabled the models
can get confused um because it might be
just like all all of these tools are
taking a lot of context right so all of
these tool descriptions and args I think
they're all going into the models
context window right so if you enable
all the tools it's going to fill up the
context window um and then I switch a
lot of models as well frequently based
on the task the reason I just switched
to composer one right now is because um
Gemini was just really really slow. Uh
and I didn't need a lot of uh accuracy
here because the the most of the work
was already done. Uh so that's why I
used um uh composer one and also I saw
the ring here and that told me that hey
for composer I'm only at 50% context. So
if it's more than 70% I would not have
used composer. I I would have probably
used 4.5 sonnet or gemini because it has
a million tokens. Um but that's the
workflow that I would always speak for
like keep looking at the context window
to make sure that you're under 50% or
70% at least. Um and then um yeah change
the models based on the task. So if I'm
reviewing any code, I always actually
use GP 5.1 codeex or GPD5 codecs because
it's extremely good at uh reviewing
code. Or like I mentioned earlier, uh
you could actually just say uh you know
um um use different models. I'm going to
use tox composer 5.1 codex and so on.
and then say um review the current git
diff uh for issues and make sure that
they follow the coding standard
>> and then question to that. So in auto
mode um isn't it supposed to be doing
that kind of optimization in the back
background you know between the
different models and providers is that
not what's happening um and then second
question is if you're using one model
versus the other like you can quickly
run out of tokens and right so how do
you prevent that right it so where
what's the point of auto mode if we're
we're switching back and forth
>> um
so there's because of the echo, it's
it's really hard to hear.
>> Uh so
what is the point of auto does auto mode
um not do that for you?
And if it does, isn't that making manual
switching pointless? Yes.
>> Yeah. Um I never use auto mode because I
want to be very selective about what
model I'm using. when you use the auto
mode, it's going to pick the best model
it thinks is for the task. Um, but
that's not what I want to do. I just
want to be selective about what model
I'm using because for complicated tasks,
for implementation, I always use 4.5
sonnet. For creating the plan, I use
GPT5 CEX, right? Um, for reviewing, I
use GP5 Codex. uh and if I've have the
plan and I would implement in parallel I
use composer and 4.5 song. So it depends
on the task you're doing but I never use
automatically because what I've realized
is that if it makes mistakes you're
actually going to end up spending way
more tokens to fix those things. So I
want to use an expensive model from the
start. So it just oneshots whatever I
want to do and then um then you end up
you're going to end up saving more time
and tokens. Um
>> okay great. Thank you.
>> I normally like start with the planning
mode. I have my own planning mode. Um so
just to give you some context on this
question like I spend about 80% of my
time in planning and only 20% with
implementation. And in planning, I
create a document that outlines every
single task. So it's it is a specdriven
dev, but I have my own mode that asks me
relevant questions every single time
before it does anything. So basically my
planning document is the exact replica
of what's going to be implemented in
code and then the model just work really
well. So that's why you need to have
different models do different things. Um
and you can basically oneshot whatever
you you want to develop. Um,
>> we have another question down the back.
>> Yep.
>> Hi, thank you. Uh, I I appreciate the
the the sharing of the models and how
the models that you're choosing models
and there's considerations about speed
as well and uh, of course token
generation and how fast these tokens are
coming through and just kind of hitting
us and you know it just kind of speeds
up development. But I'm wondering is
there is there do you have any thoughts
on um having it optimized for like
particular chips or systems specifically
like the M5 that just came out uh or
even like other uh types of like systems
or chips where where things are just
going to like really be moving around
speedily uh locally. Um, of course we're
limited to whatever the speed is online
um with with with models that are
existing um over the air, but um I was
just wondering if you had any thoughts
about um the the speed of the chips and
uh if there was any optimizations
happening behind the scenes
considerations. Thank you.
>> Um so if I'm understanding your question
correctly, you're asking if there is any
optimization on the chips that can help
uh generate tokens faster. Yeah, I think
in summary, uh you're thinking of uh
optimizing based on your experience.
>> Yeah.
>> What about optimizing for the silicon
that it's being run on? Is that right?
>> Yeah. issue.
>> Um
well, so basically if I'm understanding
your question correctly, like how do I
optimize the prompts or optimizes
workflows so that they're like more
optimized for that specific um model uh
or the specific chip that the model is
running on. Is that correct?
>> I think the capabilities like like GPUs
these days, they're moving so fast. the
hardware is moving fast and so is the
software and drivers and you know all of
that. Like is there scope for us to do
that to switch model because this works
better on Nvidia or that one works
better on AMD but only this chipset and
only with this driver that kind of stuff
which may be hard for you to see.
>> Yeah, I think it's definitely possible.
We can absolutely do do that. I can
probably u talk to him um afterwards and
explain to me explain to him like how to
achieve that but I think it's definitely
possible. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, sorry. Do you have any
recommendations for like refactoring
large code bases when you don't have all
the
>> Can you speak a little?
>> Do you have any recommendations for like
refactoring a large code base or you
know applying similar rule sets to a
large codebase?
Um you know working with legacy code as
opposed to building new features. Do you
have any recommendations?
>> Yeah. um refactoring legacy code and
kind of you know refactoring a large
code base is um a massive task and it's
really difficult um so I would normally
do it in phases so first of all I would
create a detailed plan about a specific
module on like how to refactor that
specific module and then have that that
file on the module level so kind of like
a memory or knowledge transfer file on
that specific module that tells hey this
is what this module is doing. Once you
have that, then you can basically also
try to create cursor rules for that
specific module. So that lives inside of
that module itself. And then you can
basically gradually start to work on uh
you know um each of those modules and uh
have these models test its own work as
well. And like if it's not done like it
cannot be done in one shot, right? So
you might have to like first create or
migrate everything and then have the
models tested. And the reason I said
like you have to have that knowledge
transfer file at the model level is
because it's going to tell the model
later on this is what the legacy code
was doing. This was the function and
this is how you're supposed to work. So
in the new modules as well you're going
to have the same files that that's going
to describe what that model is supposed
to do. And then when you combine all
those files and ask the mo the models to
test its own work or test the module
once the entire app is migrated it's
going to be able to figure out that hey
this was the existing feature and now
this is it does it work and you also
have to give it the context that hey
like I'm migrating or I have migrated
the old cobalt code into python or
something like that right so it knows
that hey this was a cobalt codebase and
now I'm running this now I'm seeing this
in python form form and this was the
feature before. it can understand that
hey this like I have to take care of
these things the models are smart enough
to understand that hey if I'm doing this
migration these are the issues that can
happen and it will probably help you fix
that and then creating reusable
workflows along the way to speed up the
process it's really going to help you
cuz if you're not going to create the
workflows you're going to have to like
manually prompt every single time and
that's not going to be consistent across
your entire migration and and as a
result of that you're not going to have
consistent codebase and you might
actually end up having more mistakes in
the codebase. So I think that's what I
would probably do to migrate a legacy
codebase. I hope that answers your
question.
>> It's a big project.
>> Any more final questions as we get close
to the end?
Yeah. So I think
if no more questions I think um yeah
this will be the end of um my work
workshop.
>> Thank you so much. Uh round of applause
please for
sh I I I [applause]
think I've learned a lot about uh cursor
today more than I have about anything
else having seen it in action for a good
couple of hours now. It's fantastic.
Thank you so much. And the other thing I
want to say is the Git repo that you've
been showing that's got your rules in a
lot of your rules in that's like public.
People can share that. People can use
that, learn from that. Wonderful. And we
put the link in the Zoom. It's also been
posted in our Discord. If you're not on
either of those platforms, then uh fair
enough. I won't judge you. Uh but if you
want to come and find either of us, we
can uh show you where to find uh that
replay. Actually, if you put it up
there, then people could take a photo of
it. Uh, if you want to put the git repo
up there, then we could um people would
take photos as they go away or
something. Uh, thank you once again. Uh,
next session starts at 3:00. Uh, stretch
your legs, get a drink. We'll see you at
the next one. Thank you so much.
[music]
>> [music]